Andriy Kotko

Senior Frontend Developer

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/kotkoa Github: https://github.com/Kotkoa Telegram: https://t.me/Kotkoa +34 647 18 54 06

✓ kotkoa@gmail.com

★ English: Intermediate (B2)

Pego Alicante Valencia

Summary

Frontend Developer with 6+ years of experience, I specialize in creating web applications, focusing on fintech, social media, the gig economy, and securities. My tech stack: React, TypeScript, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, Node.js, Jest, Storybook, Tailwind. I'm skilled in managing API requests, aiming to contribute to improving design systems and application UI. I'm an empathetic person who is comfortable with changes and is an incredibly fast learner and has a can-do, roll-up-your-sleeves attitude.

Technical Skills

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Typescript, Vite, Next.js, Apollo graphQl, Rest API

State management: Jotai, Mobx, react-context, Redux **CSS & Styling:** CSS modules, Tailwind, Material-UI, Radix-UI

Testing: Jest, Cypress, Yup-validation

Other: Figma, Storybook, React Drag-n-Drop, TV Lightweight Charts, JSON Forms

Version Control: Github, Gitlab, CI/CD practices

Code Quality Tools: ESLint, Prettier

Experience

From September 2022 to February 2024

Senior Frontend developer

Human Capital Exchange (HCX), Los Angeles - (Remote)

I've joined the hcx.org team as a Frontend Developer contractor to enhance a tech team of 12 persons for maintaining and refactoring an existing code of a cross-platform investment application aimed at connecting investors, sponsors, and talents on one platform.

- Designed email layout templates and marketing landing pages using Next.js, meeting strategic business and marketing objectives.
- Implemented user flows of account creation with multiple forms for various user types, regular forms, JSON Forms, Yup validation, and Apollo graphQl queries.
- Added social features, allowing users to add each other to favorites, create groups, and sort lists using the React DnD kit library.
- Optimizing the global theme of the Material-UI library by aligning main component styles with Figma to enhance library customization and consistency for reducing duplicate components.
- Continuous collaboration with the backend devs to improve the API, adding new features and fixing bugs to meet business needs.
- Removed web3 libraries, replaced blockchain operations with bank transactions, and added debit/credit card and bank account functionalities.
- Implemented user ID verification by integrating Onfido to authenticate documents and data, to meet KYC regulations.
- Enabled app evolution by migrating to an Nx Monorepo for streamlined maintenance and scaling within a single Git repository.
- Implemented legal signing by DocuSign for in-app application signings, enhancing transparency and control of user documents for marketing and legal teams.
- Covering with Jest tests and implementing the Cypress library with CI/CD integration for continuous testing of main user flows.

Technologies Used: React, Jotai, Context, Material-UI, Figma, Apollo GraphQL, React Native, JSON Forms, DnD kit, TV Chart Library, Nx Monorepo, Next.js, WordPress, Jest, Cypress, React Native, Go, Pyton

Experience

From August 2023 to January 2024

UI Developer

Yara International, Singapore - (Remote)

Hired to enhance the usability and accessibility of <u>Yara International's</u> design system, focusing on creating new components and refactoring existing ones. This role required technical proficiency and design skills to develop components within the company's design system. The project was managed in a Git repository with NxMonorepo, consolidating web (React) and mobile (React Native) libraries for developers.

- Enriched a React library with over 10 new components, and refactored existing ones, making sure they were effective and up to date.
- Conducted an accessibility audit and initiated improvements, ensuring the components meet global accessibility standards.
- Updating design system documentation to Storybook@7, optimizing infrastructure, and overhauling documentation for improved clarity and utility.
- Developed a new token structure to streamline design-to-code workflows, facilitating easier adoption of design principles and more consistent implementation across projects.
- Team Collaboration: Worked closely with designers to refine and implement component designs, discussing the overall look of the Storybook theme.
- Quality Assurance: Implemented rigorous code review and testing protocols to ensure component reliability across various browsers and devices, addressing bugs promptly to maintain system integrity.

Technologies Used: React.js, TypeScript, Jest, Storybook, Figma, Design System Library, npm, Radix-Ui, Markdown, React SPA, Girthub,

From December

2023

2022 to

September

Frontend Developer

Bridge The Gap Europe

I was recruited as a Frontend developer and UI developer to join <u>Bridge the Gap</u> Europe-based team of developers led by Varia Stepanova to enhance the team's capabilities. This role enabled me to combine my technical expertise with a keen sense of design, contributing significantly to our digital systems.

- Adding new components to the design system and publishing npm library.
- Successfully migrated the web application to Gatsby@5, improving its maintainability.
- Upgraded and modified server-side resolvers to ensure seamless functionality.

Technologies Used: React.js, Jest, GatsbyJS, Figma, Design System Library, npm, Tailwind CSS, Server Side Javascript

From

Frontend developer

December 2021 to July 2022

Root Name System (RNS), Cryptic Labs, Singapore, Los Angeles - (Remote)

I joined an international tech team as a frontend developer to enhance and manage their innovative digital identity platform, <u>rns.id</u> (Root Name System). The project aimed to develop an application by issuance of digital IDs of digital residence islands of Palau. My role was on optimizing and redesigning web applications, integrating new features of Document verifications, and elevating quality through measures such as <u>Sentry.io</u> logging, TypeScript migration, and Jest test coverage. A key part of my responsibilities included fast-forward landing page creation to meet marketing team goals.

- Spearheaded the development of React-based landing pages, web apps, and email HTML templates.
- Transferred MaterialUI concept into styled components application
- Reduced boilerplate and code complexity by migrating the web app from Redux, Redux-toolkit to MobX
- Implemented multi-site (multizone) experience (SSR and SPA) as one web app for developing both websites independently with the same level of control
- Enabled internationalization in the web app with i18n

Technologies Used: React, Next.js, Tailwind, Redux, Mobx, SASS, Mobx

2020

Freelance Fullstack Developer (React.JS & Node.JS)

Kotkoa ,Tenerife, Spain

I was acting as a full-stack engineer, creating services and endpoints with Express and frontend logic with React. I was responsible for the development of a web application for a local business. The applications were built with React, Redux, and Node.js, and were designed to be responsive and accessible across various devices.

- Integrated Javascript Playground for creating sandboxes with the ability to run and check code snippets without any need for deployment
- Migrated to clean React with Context API
- Frontend with React/Redux
- RESTful API's Node.js and Express
- Implemented low-level CSS framework Tailwind

Technologies Used: React.js. Node.js, Redux, REST API, Express, React Context, Tailwind

Experience

From 2012

Microstock's contributor

to 2021

kotkoa.com Ukraine

I used my JavaScript capabilities to create scripts that simplified the management of over 20 stores, allowing for centralized control. I used my CMS management expertise to improve and maintain the WordPress-based home page and optimize SEO through strategic keyword and tag descriptions.

Technologies Used: WordPress, HTML, CSS, SEO

From 2010 ⁹

Project Manager

to 2013

ramotion.com Ukraine

- Web Applications Graphic Design and Development
- Website Graphic Design and Development

From 2008 to 2010

From 2008 Html Developer

AllDevelop.com Ukraine

- - Creating HTML markup templates
- - Updating and modifying existing CSS code
- - Maintainance HTML content daily
- - Processing data in content at WP cms

Technologies Used: WordPress, HTML, CSS

Education

2004 - Bachelor's degree: Precision Mechanics Instruments Engineer

Technical State University Sevastopol, Ukraine

2020 - **Student:** Javascript Developer

Self-taught frontend developer using free open bits of knowledge.